宝贝?
Baby?
你吓到我了
You scared me.
抱歉
Sorry.
不是故意的
Didn't mean to.
你去过外面?
You were outside?
你为什么不叫醒我? - 我想独处
Why didn't you wake me? -I wanted to be alone.
我的意思是 清静头脑
I mean, I needed to clear my head
思绪涌动
and get the ideas flowing.
有思绪了吗
And did they?
没有
No.
会有的
They will.
不用担心
Don't worry.
会来的
It'll come.
我一定很臭 - 我喜欢
I must stink. -I like it.
我最好洗个澡
I better shower.
我能拿几个吗 - 我来拿
Can I grab these? -I got it.
完美
Perfect.
你没必要全做了
You didn't need to do all of this.
我愿意
I wanted to.
你工作太努力了
You've been working so hard.
对
Yeah. Right.
在这等着
Wait here.
不 没事的
No, no, no. It's fine. It's fine.
请进来吧 - 谢谢
Come in. Please. -Thanks. Thanks.
你好 - 你好
Hello. -Hello.
这位先生刚刚在医院上班
So this gentleman here just started working
他认为我们...
at the hospital, and he thought we were...
你负责什么? - 我是骨科医生
What do you do there? -I'm an orthopaedic surgeon.
真的?
Really?
但现在我主要从事研究和教学
But mostly now I do research and teach.
研究
Research.
这有点无聊
Yes. I know, it's a bit boring.
一点也不无聊
It's not boring at all.
坐一会儿 来一杯吗
Sit for a second. Can we get you anything to drink?
不必了
No. That isn't... That's fine.
喝茶?
Some tea?
茶? - 不
Some tea? -No, no, no, no, no.
我不...
I don't...
我不想打扰
I don't want to be a bother.
必须的
But you must.
客人兼医生?我是说 天知道
A guest and a doctor? I mean, who knows?
说不定哪天我会滚下楼梯
I might trip down the stairs one day.
希望不会吧
Let's hope not!
我去泡茶 - 谢谢
I'll go make some. -Thank you.
请这边走
This way please.
对不起 一团糟
Sorry for the mess.
装修完几个月 我们就搬进来了
We're moving in after months of construction.
不可思议的地方
It's an incredible place.
我妻子喜欢有伴
My wife loves having company.
你的妻子? - 是的
Your wife? -Yes.
我以为是你女儿
I thought it was your daughter.
请坐 - 非常感谢
Sit down. -Thank you very much.
你没事吧?
You all right?
挺好
Fine.
有个病例
Then there's this one case.
一名歌剧演唱家 近30岁
This was an opera singer, late 20s.
她的股骨朝向内侧
Her femurs were rotated so far inward
她的膝盖不能分开一英尺
that she couldn't spread her knees more than a foot apart.
真的?
Really?
谢谢 - 你改喝酒了
Thank you. -You've upgraded.
哪里来的? - 我总是随身携带
Where'd that come from? -I always carry a supply.
我从没尝过这种味道
I never tasted something like this.
很难搞到的 必须分享
It's hard to come by. I had to share.
你不来一杯吗
Won't you join?
她不太会喝酒
She's not much of a drinker.
我喝酒
I drink.
那我在你的茶里放一点
Here, let me put a little in your tea.
我喝茶就够了 谢谢
I'm fine with tea, thank you.
神医即将发表一篇重要论文
The good doctor here is about to publish a major paper.
慷慨的"关于"
"About" is generous.
我还有大量的研究要写
I still have reams of research to write up.
他搬到此间 来完成写作
And he's moved here to finish it.
什么风把你吹来了?
And... And what brings you to us?
据说这里有房间
Well, they told me I could find a room here.
他误以为我们是早餐旅店
He thought we were a bed and breakfast.
我们常说 此屋对我们俩来说太大了
We always talk about how this place is too big for the two of us.
我真的该走了 如果我要找另一间旅店...
Well, I really should be going if I'm going to find another...
胡扯 很晚了 在这里过夜吧
Nonsense. No, no. No, it's late. Stay the night.
我不能 不能
No, I couldn't. No.
我们喜欢有伴儿 对吗
Please. We'd enjoy the company, right?
当然
Yes, of course.
你确定吗 - 绝对
Are you sure? -Positive.
我把其余物件拿来
Well, then I'll just grab the rest of my stuff.
真是太好了 慷慨大方
That's incredibly kind and generous.
我放在了...
I just left it on the...
你没事吧? - 我很好
You all right? -I'm fine.
你确定?
You sure?
吸入气管了而已
Yeah. It just went down the wrong tube.
谢谢
Thanks.
我们不认识他
We don't know him.
他是个医生
He's a doctor.
他是个陌生人
He's a stranger.
就这么让他睡在我们家?
We're just gonna let him sleep in our house?
要我叫他离开?
You want me to ask him to leave?
就这些吗 - 就这些
Is that all? -That's everything.
我们不抽烟
We don't smoke.
聪明
That's smart.
我是说在房子里
In the house, I mean.
抱歉
Sorry.
我去给你拿些被铺
I'll go get you some linens.
我带你去房间 - 谢谢
I'll show you to your room. -Thank you.
再次对不起 一团糟
Once again, sorry for the mess.
没有 我真的很感激
No, please. I really appreciate this.
我喜欢这个
And this! I love this.
你怎么会有这么多副本?
How come you have so many copies?
我写的
Well, I wrote it.
天
Oh, my.
是你吗
That's you?
我是超级粉丝 - 你读过吗
I'm a huge fan. -You've read it?
我读过很多次了
I've read it many, many times.
你的书改变了我的生活
Your words have changed my life.
对不起 你一定
I'm sorry. You must...
你一定这种话听烦了
You must hear that all the time.
还没有
Not really, no.
那个
And that.
那是什么?
What is that?
小心
Careful.
非常 非常易碎
This is very, very delicate.
是礼物
It was a gift.
特别的礼物
A very special gift.
你送的吗
Is it from you?
不
No.
我小时候 一场大火 失去一切
When I was younger, I lost everything in a fire.
对不起
I'm sorry.
很难想象这意味着什么
It's hard to imagine what that means.
失去一切
Losing everything.
记忆 工作 甚至脏牙刷
Your memories, your work, even your dirty toothbrush.
我不知道我是否还能再创作
I didn't know if I could ever create again
直到我在灰烬中找到这个
until I found this in the ashes.
了不起吗
Isn't that remarkable?
我能不能...
Can I just...
它给了我重新开始的力量
It gave me the strength to start again.
然后我遇见了她
And then I met her.
你
You.
她的呼吸 使生命充满每个房间
And she breathed life back into every room.
她重生了一切
She redid all of it.
细致入微
Every last detail.
都是你自己?
By yourself?
所以你不止脸蛋漂亮
So you're not just a pretty face.
我要准备睡觉了
I just came up to say I'm gonna get ready for bed.
对不起 我没有
I'm sorry. I didn't...
你没事吧?要喝水吗
You okay? Want some water?
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
我马上就上去
I'll be up soon.
你真的不想喝水吗
Sure you don't want some water?
就一点点
Just a little bit.
给你
Here you go.
坐下
Sit down.
你只是喝多了
You just drank too much.
你很好 没事的
You're okay. It's okay.
一切都好吗
Is everything all right?
他喝得太多了 他会没事的
He drank too much. He'll be fine.
搞什么  - 给他一些隐私
What is... -Give him some privacy.
好了 吐掉
Okay, get it up.
吐干净
Just get it all up.
早安
Good morning. -Morning.
闻起来很香
Smells great.
昨晚发生什么事了?
What happened last night?
我睡不着 太兴奋了
I couldn't sleep. I got so excited.
因为什么?
From what?
他的故事 我爱他的思想
His stories. I love the man's mind.
对受众发言 更鼓舞人心
It is so inspiring speaking to someone who really appreciates the work.
我喜欢你的作品
I love your work.
当然 我知道
Of course you do. I know that.
他好点了吗
So is he better?
不好意思?
Pardon?
他感觉好点了吗
Is he feeling better?
他没事吧? - 挺好的 等一下
Is he all right? -Fine, fine. One sec.
抱歉 借个火
Sorry. Just need a light.
别担心 我去外面抽
Don't worry about it. I'll take it outside.
早安
Morning. -Good morning.
你感觉怎么样?
How are you feeling?
美妙
Wonderful.
你好多了?
You're all better?
好了点?
Better?
早安
Morning! -Morning!
睡的怎么样? - 像个婴儿
How did you sleep? -Like a baby.
鲜活的梦 一定是空气的缘故
Really vivid dreams. Must be the air.
我很困惑
Well, I'm confused.
那是谁? - 我去开
Who's that? -I'll get it.
不 我去
No, don't. I'll get it.
在等客人?
Expecting guests?
不是真的有访客
We don't really get visitors.
那会把我逼疯的
That would drive me crazy.
说说看
Tell me about it.
你好
Hello. -Hello.
我能为您效劳吗 - 你终于找到了
Can I help you? -You made it!
我的好老婆
My better half.
很高兴看到你
Nice to meet you.
我的荣幸 - 请进来吧
The pleasure is mine. -Well, come in.
没想到你结婚了
I didn't realise you were married.
不会吧?
Really?
早餐
Breakfast!
我去拿她的手提箱
I'll grab her suitcase.
着火了
It's burning.
不 不要
No, don't!
抱歉 - 我来弄
Sorry. -I got it!
坐下 - 我去开窗户
Sit down. -I'll get the windows.
让我看看
Let me look at it.
你没事吧? - 应该没事
Are you all right? -I think so.
你没事 - 冰块
You're okay. Ice.
冰块
Ice!
真笨
So stupid.
还不错 没事的 你很好
It's not bad. It's fine. You're fine.
谢谢 - 我真的很抱歉
Thank you. -I'm really so sorry.
别担心
Don't worry about it.
很高兴认识你
It's very nice to meet you.
很高兴见到你  你
Very nice to meet... You.
拜托
Oh, please!
我不再幻想浪漫了
I'd given up on romance.
我已经习惯了独处
I was getting used to being alone.
谢谢
Thank you.
但是 - 美味
But then... -Yummy.
一切发生得太快
...it just happened for us.
看到她 知道她是我想共度余生的女人
I saw her, and I knew she was the woman I wanted to spend the rest of my life with
一见钟情 - 在这里
Love at first sight. -Same here.
对
Yeah, right.
干嘛? - 我何以抗拒这张脸?
What? How could I resist this face?
你相信我吧?
You believe me, right?
来坐会儿
Come. Sit already.
你从来没有怀疑过? - 真的
So you never had a doubt? -That's true.
拜托 - 干嘛?
Yeah. Come on. -What?
你不怀疑吗 - 不 一次也没有
Didn't you have any doubts? -No! Not a one.
你懂这种关联吗
You guys understand that kind of connection, right?
你必须的
You must.
我是说你们两个很不同
I mean, you're both so different.
一定有某种纽带
It must have been what pulled you together.
你真漂亮 过来
You're so beautiful. Come here.
然后孩子们会搞砸一切
And then the kids came and screwed it all up.
你有孩子? - 两个
You have kids? -Two.
都是男孩 - 漂亮
Boys. -Beautiful.
我的长子
Here. This is my eldest.
让我看
Let me see.
她的宝贝 - 闭嘴
And then her baby. -Shut up.
漂亮的眼睛
Amazing eyes.
你们俩呢
And you two?
有孩子吗
You have kids?
还没有 但我们想要生几个
Not yet. But we want them.
那还等什么?
Well, what are you waiting for?
吃完早饭就做人吧
Why not finish breakfast and get to it?
我想把房子收拾好
Well, I want to finish the house,
他正在写新书
and he's working on a new piece.
你又在写了?
So you're writing again?
嗯
Yeah.
太好了 - 终于开动了
That's wonderful. -Finally, right?
是的
Yes.
我们妨碍你了
No. We're in the way.
这是世界上最讨厌的事...
That's the last thing in the world...
不 不必
No, no, not at all. No, no.
只要愿意 随便呆多久
You're more than welcome to stay here as long as you want.
你真是太好了
That's very kind of you.
我们不能强加意愿
No, we couldn't impose.
亲爱的 他们有足够的房间
Honey, they've got plenty of room.
说到孩子 你有电话吗 我手机没有信号
Speaking of kids, do you have a phone? I can't get a signal.
我们就喜欢如此
That's how we like it.
你不必每天给他打电话
You don't have to call him every day.
厨房里有一部 我领你去
There's one in the kitchen. I can show you.
不用 没事的
No, it's all right.
我们能在周末放松一下吗
Can we just relax for the weekend?
不 亲爱的 我只想他知道我们很好
No, honey, I just want to let him know we're okay.
简单电话一声
Just a quick call.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
你为什么不先问我?
Why would you do that without asking me?
问什么? - 邀请他们留下来
Do what? -Invite them to stay.
我认为这不算什么大事
I didn't think it was a big deal.
很奇怪  - 哪里奇怪?
It's strange. -What?
你知道他有妻子吗
Did you know he had a wife?
你的写作怎么办?
What about your writing?
我真的很享受不去思考写作
I was actually enjoying not thinking about it.
但现在我得仔细思考了
But now that I am thinking about it,
我应该做点什么
I should go and do something about it.
我真的该工作了
I really should work.
柠檬水
Lemonade!
小心
Careful.
我想你可能会喜欢
Thought you might like some.
谢谢
Yes, thank you.
祖传秘方
Secret family recipe.
哪一部分?柠檬?
Which part? The lemons?
你的手怎么样?
How's your hand?
仍然刺痛 - 对不起
Still stinging. -I'm sorry.
不像是你的错
It's not like it was your fault.
你没有止痛药吧?
You don't have any painkillers, do you?
你说的是真话?
Are you telling me the truth?
我真的没有止痛药 对不起
I really don't have any. I'm sorry.
OK
Okay.
你不渴吗
You're not thirsty?
对
Right.
现在我明白了
Now I get it.
味道强劲 - 我第二杯了
It's strong. -I'm on my second.
真不敢相信你自己做了这些事
I can't believe you did all this work yourself.
为什么不呢 - 工程浩大
Why not? -It's a lot.
我们会长久在这里
Well, we spend all our time here.
我想让它成为天堂
I want to make it paradise.
我喜欢干活
And I love the work.
很精致
And it's exquisite.
谢谢
Thank you.
你能带我参观吗
Would you take me on a tour?
当然
Sure.
感谢你的盛情款待
I want to thank you for your hospitality.
你丈夫太友善了
Your husband has been so generous.
不客气
You're welcome.
那么 从哪里开始呢
Well, where to begin?
最麻烦的地方
Well, this was the hardest part.
磨损巨大 踏面都消失了
There was so much damage. The treads were gone,
栏杆 甚至天窗
the railing, even the skylight.
所以我得买很多新材料
So I had to get a lot of new material,
但我尽量节省
but I tried to save as much...
比毛胚房还难吗
Isn't it a lot harder than just starting fresh?
你是什么意思?
How do you mean?
你为什么不建个新房子?
Why didn't you just build a new house?
因为
Well, it's...
这是他的家
It's his home.
你真的爱他
You really love him.
我能问你一个问题吗
Can I ask you a question?
你为什么不想要孩子?
Why don't you want kids?
对不起?
Excuse me?
我看到你之前的反应了
I saw how you reacted earlier.
我知道初期的感觉
I know what it's like when you're just starting out,
你以为有全世界所有的时间
and you think you have all the time in the world.
你要知道 你不会永远年轻
You know, you're not going to be so young forever.
得生孩子
Have kids.
然后你们会齐心协力
Then you'll be creating something together.
才能保证婚姻的连续
That's what keeps a marriage going.
都只是为了
This... This is all just
按部就班
setting.
你想要他们的
You do want them.
是他的缺陷?
Is it him?
我得回去工作了 - 那他为什么说...
I'm gonna get back to work. -Then why did he say...
对不起
I'm sorry.
我太八卦了吗 我常犯这毛病
Was I too forward? I do that sometimes.
每段关系都有自己的问题
Every relationship has its issues.
你们之间隔了整整一代
And when there's a full generation between you,
所以我只能想象
I can only imagine.
那是他工作的地方吗
Is that where he works?
那是私人的
That's private.
不能给我瞄一眼吗
Can't you just give me a peek?
他不喜欢有人单独闯入
He doesn't like anyone being in there without him!
你真的爱他
You really do love him.
上帝保佑你
God help you.
你要去哪里?
Where are you going?
我要带他出去 - 我们要去远足
I'm gonna take him outside. -We're going on a hike.
远足?
A hike?
我徒步旅行 - 快速的
Me on a hike! -Just a quick one.
慢点走
Go slow.
足够慢 免得烟烧得太快
Yeah, slow enough so my smoke doesn't burn too quickly.
你不想来吗 - 不 我们有衣服要洗
You don't want to come? -No, we have laundry to do.
你会让我看的吧?
You'll show me where, right?
哪条路? - 无所谓
Which way? -Doesn't matter.
你不觉得这俩男人惺惺相惜吗
The boys have bonded, don't you think?
我家男人通常没有这么率性
Mine's not usually such a nature boy.
我猜你还没到这个程度
Guess you haven't quite got to this part yet.
这太重了
This is so heavy.
很多工具
That's a lot of tools.
我去拿
I'll get it.
哪一个? - 在左边
Which is which? -On the left.
满了
It's full.
等等 我来帮你
Wait! I'll help you.
不 找到问题所在了
No. So that's the problem.
什么?
What?
穿这么保守怎么行?
You're gonna have to try harder than this.
对不起
I'm sorry.
相信我 当男人老了
Believe me, when they get older,
你得保持情趣
you got to keep it interesting.
他没那么老
He's not that old.
老干部活动中心还好吗
How's it going in that department?
我不喜欢谈论那种事情
I don't feel comfortable talking about that stuff.
我只是想帮忙
I'm just trying to help.
我是说看看你
I mean, look at you.
如果他对你没有全心全意
If he's not all over you,
不是因为他的年龄或
it's either because of his age or...
或什么?
Or what?
知道吗 算了
You know what? Forget it.
这不关我的事
It's none of my business.
我想我上头了
I think this has gone to my head.
没事的 说说清楚
No, it's okay. Say what you were gonna say.
意思是他还爱你
No, seriously. No, obviously he still loves you.
我去梳洗一下
I'm gonna freshen these up.
你好?
Hello?
我告诉过你 他不喜欢有人单独闯入
I told you, he doesn't like anyone being in here without him.
太神奇了 这是什么?
It's amazing. What is it?
我们真的得走了
We really have to leave.
拜托? - 我只想看看
Please? -I just want to look at it.
你得走了
You have to go.
我不知道你为什么小题大做
I don't know why you have to make such a big deal of it.
他们回来了
They're back.
这边 - 亲爱的?
This way. Here. -Honey?
给你拿点水来 - 你没事吧?
Let's get you some water. -Are you all right?
这可恶的烟
Your damn smoking.
拿着
Here.
你没事吧? - 刚刚开始
You all right? -Just started.
我们去给你拿药
Come on. Let's go get you your pills.
如果我想要第三个孩子
If I wanted a third child...
我猜你太过火了
I guess you overdid it.
太紧张了
That was intense.
你不会相信他刚告诉我的
And you won't believe what he just told me.
那个水槽还没准备就绪
That sink's not braced yet.
什么?
What?
等等
Wait.
怎么了?
Something happened?
什么?
What?
怎么了?说话
What is it? What?
他的行李里有你的一张照片
He has one of those pictures of you in his luggage.
你翻他们行李做什么?
What were you doing in their luggage?
这不是重点
That's not the point.
他并非碰巧找到我们的
He didn't just stumble on us.
他是个狂热的粉丝 - 我知道
He's a crazy fan. -I know.
不好意思?
Excuse me?
刚才他告诉我了
That's what he told me on our walk.
他要死了
He's dying.
所以他才来这里
That's why he came here.
他想离世之前见我
He wanted to meet me before he's gone.
那他为什么不告诉我们?
Well, why didn't he tell us that?
为什么撒谎? - 我不知道
Why lie? -I don't know. I don't know.
他是个骄傲的人
He's a proud man.
我很佩服
I admire that.
你做了什么? - 对不起
What have you done? -I'm so sorry.
我们都很抱歉 我正在告诉她故事...
We're both sorry. I was telling her the story and...
然后我就手滑了
It just... It just fell out of my hand.
我们会为您另找一件 - 我们可以付钱
We'll search and find you another one. -We can pay for it.
安静
Quiet!
很抱歉我吼了 我想静静
I'm sorry I screamed. I just need a moment.
这是个意外
It was an accident.
我想你们最好离开
I think it's best if you leave.
我们说了对不起
We said we were sorry.
亲爱的别争辩 - 你还想怎样?
Honey, don't antagonise her. -Well, what more do you want?
不会有事的
Just... It'll be okay.
拜托
Please.
Please!
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
他们再也进不来了
They will never get in here again.
别担心 我要赶他们走
Well, don't worry. I'm kicking them out.
他们能去哪里?
Yeah. And where will they go?
需要什么吗
Need something?
你准备好了吗 - 什么意思?
Are you ready? -What do you mean?
你们得离开
We want you out.
我们?还是你?
We? Or you?
我已经努力过了  - 好吧 听着
I've tried very hard... -Yeah, well, look,
我得去看看我丈夫
I have to check on my husband.
你好?
Hello? Hello!
大家都去哪了?
Where is everybody?
你是谁?
Who are you?
你是谁?你在这里干什么?
Who are you? What are you doing here?
我们所有人不都是吗
What are any of us doing here, right?
我妈妈在哪里?
Where's my mother?
她...请等在这里
She's... Wait here.
风景不错
Nice view.
你邀请了你儿子吗 - 你来做什么?
Did you invite your son? -What are you doing here?
妈妈 我打过电话 但没能打通
Mom, I tried calling, but I couldn't get through.
怎么了?
What's wrong?
他来到家里 找到了遗嘱
He came to the house and found the will.
什么? - 对 他失控了
What? -Yeah, he's out of control.
对不起 不管什么情况
I'm sorry, but whatever this is,
你们得先离开 - 爸爸
you'll have to finish this... -Dad!
他在此? - 不!
He's here? -What? No.
那是谁? - 爸爸
Who's that? -Dad! Dad!
直接跑去妈妈那里
Yeah, ran straight to Mommy.
你跟踪我 你什么毛病?
You followed me. What's wrong with you?
你不该在这里的 - 爸爸呢 他在哪?
You shouldn't be here. -Where's Dad? Where is he?
她是谁?你是谁?
Who is she? Who are you? Who are you?
他不想见你 - 那不是真的 他在不在?
He doesn't want to see you. -That's not true. Is he here?
爸爸 - 儿子们?
Dad! -Boys?
孩子们 你们怎么来了?
Boys, why are you here?
这是什么?知道你签了什么?
What is this? Do you know what you've signed?
当然知道 - 回去躺下
Of course I do! -Go lie back down.
你说已经告诉他了的
You said that you told him.
没有 亲爱的 我是说我正要告诉他
No, honey, I didn't say that. I was going to.
你想要这个?你怎么能这样?
You wanted this? How could you?
我自有道理 儿子
It's for a good reason, son.
让我解释给他听
Let me explain to him.
我跟他说 - 不 由我跟他解释
I'll talk to him. -No, I'll talk to him.
你是对的 我应该亲自告诉你的
You're right. I should have told you myself.
抱歉 我保证我有考虑过你
And I'm sorry. I promise you that I was thinking about you.
住手 这样对大家都好 - 听爸爸的话
Stop it! About what's best for all of us. -Just listen to Dad!
这是信任 做出的决定
It's a trust. You have to make a decision
必须考虑所有人 免得无谓
as a group before anything can be spent.
这行不通 难道我连小便也要他们许可?
It won't work. I have to get permission from them every time I take a piss?
这样会迫使你和睦相处
It will force you to get along.
这才最重要
That's the most important thing.
她每次都支持他 - 你没在听我说话
She will side with him every time. - You're not listening to me!
支持我?
Support me?
你只想对我指手画脚
You just want to tell me what I can and can't do.
这不公平
That is not fair!
你从来不相信我或我的所为
You never believe in me or anything I try to do.
别这样 爸爸 他们恨我
Don't do this, Dad. They hate me!
他们不恨你 - 我们爱你
They don't hate you. -We love you.
你是我的儿子
You're my son.
那就把我当儿子
Well, then treat me like one!
儿子们来了
The sons are here.
他们这样闯进来 我无法阻止
They just barged in. I couldn't stop them.
我知道
I know.
如果不是你浪费了一切
Yeah, if you don't waste it all.
闭嘴 - 又来了
Shut up! -Here we go again.
他没有得偿所愿 脾气就失控
Losing his temper when he doesn't get his way.
我们去外面讨论吧 主人来了
Let's discuss this outside. Our hosts are here.
不 我现在就想谈谈
No! I want to talk about it now.
我现在就想谈谈 爸爸 - 闭嘴
I want to talk about it now, Dad. -Shut up!
如果你需要钱 我会给你钱
If you need money, I'll give you money.
我不想你的零钱
I don't want your chump change!
别碰我
Don't touch me!
冷静 冷静
Calm down. Calm down.
你是诗人?伟大的作家?
You're the poet? The great writer?
你什么都不知道
You don't know anything.
他们骗了我 他们在抢劫我
They lied to me. They're robbing me.
我不知道他们的故事 但你冷静先?
I don't know their story, but will you calm down?
行不行?
Will you?
谢谢
Thank you.
你可以坐在那里
You can sit in there.
我们坐下来讨论一下
Let's go sit down and discuss this.
不 妈妈 爸爸要死了
No! Mom, Dad's dying,
他只关心他的钱
and all he cares about is his damn money!
不 住手 - 孩子们 住手
No! Stop it! -Boys! Boys, stop it!
看看爸爸 看看你做了什么
Look at Dad! Look what you did!
住手
Stop!
孩子们 住手
Boys! Stop it!
住手
Stop! Please!
你能呼吸吗 呼吸
Can you breathe? Breathe.
不
No!
过来 - 等等 住手
Come here! -Wait! Stop!
你有什么毛病? - 住手
What's wrong with you? -Stop it!
不 住手
No! Stop!
不
No!
不 不
No! No!
放开
Get off!
起来
Get up.
Get up! Get up!
别装了 起来
Stop faking. Get up.
起来 看着我
Get up. Look at me!
不 不是我的错
No. It's not my fault.
不是我的错 他们从来没有真正爱过我
It's not my fault. They never really loved me.
他们总是更爱他 弃我于不顾
They always loved him more. They were leaving me behind.
告诉我你懂
Just tell me you understand.
Tell me you understand!
你必须懂
You have to understand.
你对你兄弟干了什么?
What have you done to your brother?
宝贝
My baby. My baby.
你做了什么?
What did you do?
是你干的
You did this.
醒醒 做点什么 帮帮他
Wake up! Do something! Help him!
毛巾 - OK
Towels. Towels. -Okay.
现在放松 - 父亲
Easy now. -Father...
医生 去找他 - OK
The doctor. Go get him. -Okay.
快来 - 干嘛?
Come quick! -What?
发生什么事了? - 他在流血
What's happening? -He's bleeding.
太糟糕了 真的很糟糕 - 他醒不过来
It's bad! It's really bad. -He's not waking up. He's not waking up.
小心 别掉下去
Careful. Careful! Don't drop him.
我会从医院给你打电话
I'll call you from the hospital.
保持头部扬起 - 不要 请和我在一起
Keep his head up. -No! No, please stay with me.
不他 我们需要你丈夫
Please, we need him.
锁门 我会尽快回来的
Lock the doors. I'll be back as soon as I can.
请不要离开我
Please don't leave me! Please don't leave me!
他们丢下你一个人?
They left you all alone?
你是个明白人
You do understand.
祝你好运
Good luck.
911 什么急事?
911. What's your emergency?
你有什么急事?
What's your emergency?
你没事吧?
You all right?
有个人
He was here!
我知道 警察送我回家的
I know. I know. The police brought me home.
他们会找到他的 不用担心
They'll find him. Don't worry.
他伤害你没有? - 没有
Did he hurt you? -No.
没有? - 没有
No? -No.
OK
Okay.
好的 坐下
Okay, sit.
我给你拿点水来
Let me get you some water.
给你
Here.
没事了
It's okay.
It's all right.
医院怎么样?
What happened at the hospital?
他死的时候 我握着那男孩的手
I was holding the boy's hand when he died.
太可怕了
That's awful.
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
我累坏了
I'm exhausted.
我要洗个热水澡
I need a hot shower.
你来吗
Will you come?
嗯
Yeah.
这是什么?
What is it?
我一会儿就上来 - 你确定?
I'll be up in a minute. -You sure?
嗯
Yeah.
在这里?
In here?
穿过厨房直走
Yeah, straight ahead in the kitchen.
他们很快就回来了
They came back quick.
他们在这里做什么?
What are they doing here?
他们无处可去
They had nowhere to go,
所以我告诉他们 不如邀请朋友和家人
so I told them it would be all right to invite some friends and family.
我去安排他们
I'll go deal with them.
对不起 - 谢谢
I'm so sorry. -Thank you.
很抱歉你的损失
I'm so sorry for your loss.
但这里欢迎你们
You're all so welcome here.
请你们随意
Please make yourselves at home.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry.
要不要来一杯?
Shall we have a toast?
好啊
Yes, let's.
确保每人一杯
Make sure everyone has one.
你能说点什么吗
Would you say something?
他很尊重你
He so respects you.
当然 - 谢谢
Of course. -Thank you.
诸位
Everyone.
如何明白你的痛苦
Well, how can one begin to understand your pain?
父母的牺牲
The sacrifice of the parent.
给你
Here you go.
这么多年的担心
All those years of worry.
每天每时每秒
Years in days, days in hours, hours in seconds.
但每一秒
But in each second,
都是无限的爱
an infinite amount of love.
现在
And now,
突然
suddenly,
似乎没有什么值得爱的了
it seems there is nothing to love.
巨大而寂寥的黑暗
Just a vast and silent darkness.
但不要害怕
But fear not.
内心 有个声音在呼喊着
From inside it, there's a voice crying out to be heard,
响亮强烈
loud and strong.
听听
Just listen.
天啊
Oh, God.
你听到了吗
Do you hear that?
听到了吗 生命的声音
Do you hear that? That is the sound of life.
人类的声音
That is the sound of humanity.
你儿子的声音
That is your son's voice.
他爱的呼声
His cry of love.
他对你的爱
His love for you.
谢谢 - 我的荣幸
Thank you. -My pleasure.
听
Hear, hear!
今晚谢谢大家
Thank you all for coming here and being with us tonight.
我夫妻二人都很感动
My husband and I are so touched.
我们今天失去了孩子
We lost our baby today.
我无法...
I just...
仅仅几小时前
I can't believe that just a few hours ago,
他站在那里 我抱着他
he was standing there, and I was holding him in my arms.
他充满了生命气息
He was so full of life.
他一直都是
He always was.
你好 - 谢谢
Hello. -Thank you.
这个放在哪里? - 这里好了
Where should I put this? -Maybe in here.
现在他再也不会流浪了
Now he'll never wander again.
我再也不会像今天这样抱着他了
I'll never hold him again like I did today.
他不会再笑了
He'll never laugh again.
我只想感谢你们的到来
I just want to thank you all for being here.
这意味着很多 我不知道还能说什么
It means so much. I don't know what else to say.
感谢主人的盛情款待
I just want to thank our dear host for his hospitality
真是及时雨 - 当然
in our time of need. -Of course.
请吧
So, please,
我想为你的好意干杯
I'd like to drink to your kindness.
对不起
Excuse me.
亲爱的 你不必这么做
Sweetheart, you don't have to do this.
我愿意
No, I want to.
我爱我的儿子
I loved my son.
我爱他
I loved him.
真不敢相信
I can't believe this.
但我不应该赞扬他
But I shouldn't be eulogising him.
他会说
He'd say...
对不起
I'm sorry...
对不起 我不能
I'm sorry. I can't.
拜托有谁...
Would someone please...
说点什么
Would you say something?
我
I...
为了你的孩子
For your child.
为了你的孩子 来
For both your children. Come.
别忘了还在荒野中的那个
Let's not forget the one still in the wilderness.
无论他去哪里 无论他在哪里
Wherever he goes, wherever he is...
欢迎 请加入我们
Welcome. Please join us.
我要把这个放进厨房
I'm just gonna put this in the kitchen.
穿过那里
Yes, through there.
愿他能找到仁慈和慈悲
May he find kindness, compassion...
我在这里等 - 我马上回来
I'll wait here. -I'll be right back.
你好吗
Hey, how you doing?
我很好
I'm good, considering.
对不起 你能从那里下来吗
Excuse me. Could you get down from there?
那个水槽还不能用
That sink's not braced yet.
对不起
I'm sorry.
这里有玻璃
There's glass here.
太美了 不是吗
That was so beautiful, no?
没事了
It's all right.
可以借用电话吗
Can I use your phone?
当然 在厨房里
Sure. It's in the kitchen.
不 只是...
No, it's just...
对不起?
Excuse me?
你去哪里了?
Where did you go?
我只是在...
I was just in the...
我真的很抱歉
I'm really sorry, again.
我知道你抱歉
I know you are.
我无法想象  - 不
I can't imagine... -No.
你无法想象 没有孩子会是什么感觉
You can't imagine what it feels like if you don't have a child.
你不停付出
You give, and you give, and you give, and...
永远不够
It's just never enough.
我明白 - 是吗
I understand. -Do you?
你为什么不穿点像样的?
Why don't you at least put on something decent?
你不能在这里
You can't be in here.
对不起? - 你们得离开
I'm sorry? -You need to leave.
就一会儿 - 这是我们的房间
We'll just be a minute. -This is our room!
算了
It's okay.
你们的房间
It's your room.
我们再找个地方
Come on. Let's find another spot.
对不起
Excuse me.
只是随便看看
Just exploring.
对不起
Excuse me.
请你们下楼去好吗
Could you please go downstairs?
这边? - 是的
This way? -Yes.
当然
Sure.
搞什么
What is...
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
没什么大不了的
It's no big deal.
我大学念的就是这科
I worked my way through college doing this.
你为什么要粉刷我的房子?
But why are you painting my house?
他对每个人都很好
Well, he's been so kind to everyone,
这是我们力所能及的
it's the least we could do.
住手
Stop!
你们俩住手
Both of you. Stop!
没关系
No problem.
当然 我的就是你的
Yes, of course. What's mine is yours.
你来了 我的女神 过来
There you are! My goddess. Come here.
请给她腾点地方 谢谢 过来
Please, make some room for her. Thank you. Here.
你一定要听这些故事
You've got to hear these stories.
所有这些人
All these people!
我知道 他们只是在发泄
I know. They're just letting off steam.
他们在粉刷我们的房子
They're painting our house!
你没事吧?
You all right?
我叫你别再喝酒了
I told you to stop drinking.
我来
I got it.
餐巾 - 我有
Napkins! -Yeah, I got some.
你没事吧?
Are you all right?
椅子可能不太好
The chair might not be all right.
和妈妈呆了几天之后...
After spending a few days with my mother...
拜托 从那里下来
Please! Get down from there.
抱歉
Sorry.
对不起
Excuse me.
她有什么问题? - 我不知道
What's her problem? -I don't know.
我们还没见过
We haven't met.
我认识这家人很多年了 你呢
I've known this family for years. And you?
这是我的房子
This is my house.
美丽的家 去散散步吗
Well, it's a beautiful home. You want to take a walk?
什么? - 散步 和我一起
What? -A walk. With me.
不
No. No.
拜托
Please!
拿我的号码 - 不 我不想要你的号码
Take my number. -No, I don't want your number.
你为什么这么说?你根本不了解我
Why would you say that? You don't even know me.
给你电话号码
Let me give you my number.
放开我 - 为什么?
Let go of me! -Why?
因为我不认识你
Because I don't know you.
从那里下来 - 从哪里来?
Get down from there. -From where?
你不知道我能为你做什么
You don't know what I could do for you.
我不想要你的任何东西
I don't want anything from you.
无礼
Sassy.
别烦我
Leave me alone.
不如你滚开吧
You know what? Get out of my face.
傲慢的婊子
You're an arrogant cunt.
这个水槽没有问题
This sink. There's nothing wrong with it.
真的很好
It's really okay.
别这样 住手
No, stop doing that. Don't do that. Stop!
Stop doing that! Stop, stop!
出去 你们都给我滚出去
Get out! Get out, all of you!
怎么了?
What happened?
他们不会听的
They won't listen!
没关系 我们会修好的 能修好
It's all right. We'll fix it. It can be fixed.
我们正受到惩罚 - 求你别走 别走
We're being punished. -Please, don't go. Don't go.
我们会关掉水阀 - 很荣幸
We'll turn it off. -It's been an honour.
永远不会忘记你为我们所做的一切
We will never forget all you've done for us.
你们要去哪里?
Where will you go?
他们都走了
They're gone.
我们去睡觉吧 你不必如此的
Come. Let's go to bed. You don't need to do that.
如此什么?
Do what?
清理他们的烂摊子?
Clean up their mess?
我们做了件好事
We did a good thing.
他们需要地方来庆祝人生
They needed a place to celebrate life.
今晚就需要
They needed tonight.
那我的需要呢
What about what I needed?
今天有个男孩死在这里 我擦了他的血
A boy died here today. I mopped up his blood.
你抛弃了我 - 不 我没有抛弃你
And you abandoned me. -No, no, I didn't abandon you.
他们刚失去一个儿子 是两个儿子
They just lost a son. They lost, well, two sons!
我在帮他们 与我们无关 关于他们的
I was helping them. This is not about us. It's about them.
不是关于他们 是关于你的
No! It's not about them. It's about you.
总是与你和你的工作有关
It's always about you and your work.
这能帮你写作?
You think that's gonna help you write?
什么都没有
Nothing does!
我重建了整栋房子 墙连墙
I rebuilt this entire house, wall to wall.
你一句话都没写出来
You haven't written a word!
我知道 对不起  我不能写作
I know! I know! I'm sorry! I can't... I can't write!
我没有思路
I can't think!
我要做的 就是把生命带进这房子
All I'm trying to do is bring life into this house!
开门纳入新人 新的想法
Open the door to new people, new ideas.
你认为你不能呼吸?
You think you can't breathe?
我要窒息于此了
I'm the one who's suffocating here
而你却假装一切正常
while you pretend that nothing is wrong!
"一切都会好的"
"Everything will be all right. Everything will be good. You'll be fine."
生活不如意 十有八九
You know what? Life doesn't always work out the way you want it to.
你是对的
You're right.
我不对
Mine certainly didn't.
对不起?
Excuse me?
你说要孩子 但你都不干我
You talk about wanting kids, but you can't even fuck me.
过来 - 不
Come here. Come here! -No! No!
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
我们要有孩子了
We're gonna have a baby.
我是认真的
I'm serious.
你怎么知道?
How could you know?
因为我知道
Because I know.
我怀孕了
I'm pregnant.
孩子
A baby.
你开心吗 - 开心?
Are you happy? -Happy?
最赞的礼物
That's the most beautiful gift.
干嘛?
What?
钢笔
Pen, pen, pen.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
我在写字
I'm writing.
什么? - 写作
What? -Writing.
昨晚那些人
Last night, those people.
他们的痛苦 先苦后爱 然后
Their pain. Their love behind the pain. And then...
你
You.
我们
Us.
现在
And now that.
生命
Life.
文思泉涌
It's coming to me. It's...
我有想法了 只需写出来便成
I know what to say. I have to find the words. That's all.
惊人
Amazing.
我不
Well, I won't...
我不想打断你
I don't want to interrupt.
我去准备启示录(育婴)
I'll just get started on the apocalypse.
我爱你
I love you.
它动了
It moved!
怎么了
What is it?
完成了?
Is that it?
我完成了
I finished it.
可以吗
May I?
真漂亮
It's beautiful.
真的?
Really?
你为什么哭?
Why are you crying?
只是忍不住
It's just a lot.
你觉得好吗
You think it's good?
太完美了
It's perfect.
但这是怎么了?
But then what's going on?
我会失去你吗
Am I going to lose you?
永不
Never.
你好?
Hello?
你好
Hi.
怎么?
Yes?
真的?
Really?
不会吧 - 那是谁?
Really. -Who is that?
给我一秒钟 他们很喜欢
One moment. Give me a second. They loved it.
谁喜欢?
Who did?
我马上就来 请稍后
What? Yeah, I'll be here, standing by.
你在吗 喂?
Are you there? Hello?
那是谁? - 我的出版商
Who was that? -My publisher.
她读过了? - 当然 怎么了?
She's read it? -Yes. Of course. Why?
是
Yes.
嗨 又来了
Hi, again.
出版?你知道我的想法
Press? Well, you know how I feel about it.
我宁愿不 除非你认为必须
I'd rather not. But if you think it's a must.
我会在这里等你
I'll be here, waiting.
惊人
Amazing!
我们在庆祝
Well, we're celebrating.
书在一天内售罄
One day, every copy sold.
你真漂亮
You're so beautiful.
让自己舒服点 其余我来
Make yourself comfortable. I'll go get everything.
看起来很好吃
Looks delicious.
让我帮你 - 不 坐下
Let me help you. -No, sit.
我帮下较好 - OK
No, I'm helping. -Okay.
你能带些面包吗
Will you bring the bread in?
好吧
All right.
请等一下 我能见见他吗
No. Wait, please. Can I see him?
对不起 我有个问题
Excuse me. I have a question.
你们做什么?
What are you doing?
他们是谁? - 我不知道
Who are they? -I don't know.
请等等 - 等等
Please. Wait. -Wait.
他们想要什么?
What do they want?
我不知道 他们是来找我的
I don't know. They've come here to see me.
求你了 我只是想和他合影
Please, I just want to take a photo with him.
他一会儿就回来
He'll be back in a moment.
晚餐先暖着 我马上就来
Just keep everything warm. I'll be right in.
就一个提问
You had a question.
嗯 - 是什么?
Yeah. -What is it?
正如我所说 我们都走了很远
As I was saying, we've all travelled a great distance,
我觉得
and I feel that...
这些语句
Well, these words,
我觉得他们写的是我
I feel like they were written for me.
当然了
Of course they were.
我的女神 过来
My goddess! Come here.
来
Come.
离我远点 - 请离开她 谢谢
No, stay away from me! -Please leave her. Thank you.
他们喜欢书 他们全都理解
They love it. They understand all of it.
但书以不同的方式影响着每个人
But it affects everyone in a different way.
非常了不起 来吧 他们想见你
It is remarkable. Come. They want to meet you.
我不想去 进屋吧
No, I don't want to. I don't want to. Come inside.
但他们走了那么远
But they've come from so far.
看着我
Look at me!
我要有孩子了
I'm about to have our baby.
对你来说 还不够?
Why is that not enough for you?
当然够了
Of course it's enough.
我哪儿也不去 我在这里陪你
I'm not going anywhere. I'm here, with you.
我想和你独处
I want to be alone with you.
我和你一起
I'm with you.
给我一秒钟
Give me a second.
来吧 快点
Come, come, come. Quick, quick.
等一下
Just hang in there. Hold it in.
那边有个卫生间 应该很近
I'm sure there's a bathroom really close.
等等 - 对不起
Hold it in. -Excuse me.
你知道洗手间在哪里吗
Do you know where the bathroom is?
你得离开 - 我该去哪里?
You need to leave. -Where should I go?
我不知道 但你不能在这里
I don't know, but you can't be in here.
但我的儿子 他
But my son, he...
跟我来
Okay. Come with me.
非常感谢 我会回来收拾干净的
Thank you so much. I'll come back and clean up.
是你打开的?
Did you open this?
OK 再多一点点时间
Okay, here we go. Just a little bit longer.
没关系 我们会把你弄干的
It's okay. We'll get you dried off.
完后 你们必须回到外面去
After you've finished, I really need you to go back outside.
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
给点隐私好吗
How about a little privacy?
拜托?
Please?
先生
Sir!
我已经等了很长时间了 对不起
I've been waiting a long time. Excuse me.
派对 女士 - 不
Wait your turn, lady! -No!
你们怎么进来的?
How did you get in here?
我们两人行吗
Could you get the two of us, please?
我弄好了 - 谢谢
No, I got it. I got it. -Thanks.
好了 蹲下 - 太美了
Okay, get down on the floor. -It's beautiful.
别碰那个
Don't touch that!
非常有生机
It's so organic.
别推了
Stop pushing!
你们都要出去
All of you need to go outside.
先生
Sir!
我想躺下休息 我感觉不太好
I'm just gonna lie down for a bit. I don't feel so good.
不 你不能躺在这里 - 为什么 你住这里?
No, no, you cannot lie down here. -Why? You staying in here?
我住在这里 这是我的房子
I live here. This is my house.
"我的房子"?"我的房子"?
"My house"? "My house"?
诗人说 这是所有人的家
The poet says it's everyone's house!
食物和饮料 我的朋友
Food and drink, my friends.
我相信就在后面
I believe it's, yes, right back here.
这很好 我们有蔬菜
This is nice. We've got vegetables...
住手 你们所有人
Stop! All of you.
检查一下橱柜还有冰箱
Check the cabinets. And the fridge!
你在做什么?
What are you doing?
美丽
Beautiful!
不 那不是给你的
No! No! That's not for you.
他说要分享
He said to share.
但这不是你的
But it's not yours!
他们又饥又渴 给你
They're hungry and thirsty. Here you go.
现在 拿水果 奶酪和泡菜
Now, take the fruit and the cheese and the pickles.
对不起 小心你的后背
Excuse me. Watch your backs.
你可以放在那里 去那边
You can put that over there. And that goes over there.
看起来不错 我们一起分享吧
Looks great. Let's share it.
我把这切成薄片
I'll slice this up.
你可以坐这儿 先生
You can sit here, sir.
没有照片 只是签名
There'll be no photos, just autographs!
你的文笔真美
Your writing is so beautiful.
这是什么?你在做什么?
What is this? What are you doing?
我向他们展示我的感激之情
I'm showing them my appreciation.
你好
Hi!
我的天才
My genius.
看看你
Look at you.
第二本出版物 - 好极了
The second printing is here. -Great.
我希望你能告诉我这次集会
Yes. I wish you would've told me about this turnout.
来见见我的... - 她来了
Have you met my... -There she is.
灵感
The inspiration.
好吧 我得说实话
All right, I have to be honest.
我有点担心 他会和你一起躲在这里
I was a little worried about him being holed up here with you.
我很紧张 你再也不写了
I was nervous you'd never write again.
当然不是
Of course not.
但不管你做了什么 都是值得的
But whatever you did, it was worth it.
看看你 你已经准备好了
And look at you. You're ready to pop!
感觉怎么样 热吗
How are you feeling? Hot?
这里很热 是不是因为我?我很焦灼
It's hot in here. Is it me? It's broiling.
我把它放在这里
I've got it right here.
请原谅
Yes. Will you excuse me?
让我想想 把它拿出来
Let me see. Take it out!
这正是我想要的
Yes. That's exactly what I wanted.
原件在哪里? - 就在桌子那边
The original, where is it? -It's right there by the desk.
我知道了 - 对不起
I've got it! -Excuse me.
我明白了 - 我要了 谢谢
I've got it. -I'll take that, thank you.
没关系 - 别碰它
No, it's okay. -No, don't touch it!
没事 - 别碰它
No, it's fine. -Don't touch it!
把你的手拿开 - 发生什么事了?
No! Get your hands off it! -What happened?
等等 放松
Wait, wait! Easy, easy, easy.
我想一起合影进去
I'm trying to put it in this frame.
我来了 一切都好
Okay, I'll do it. It's all good.
住手 还给我
Stop! Give that back. Give it back.
不 我必须拥有他的东西 不
No, I have to have something of his! No!
是我的
It's mine!
你干的 现在我不得不另找一件了
You did it! Now I got to find something else!
出去 你们所有人
Get out! All of you!
住手 这不属于你们
Stop! This doesn't belong to you!
911 什么情况?
911. What is your emergency?
你可以帮我吗
Can you help me?
你有什么急事 夫人?
What is your emergency, ma'am?
他们在偷东西
They're stealing everything!
谢谢
Thank you.
电话我正在用
I was using that!
没关系 分享 就像诗人说的
That's all right. Share, like the poet said.
对 分享
Yeah, share.
那是不对的
That's not right.
看 他给你做了记号
Look, he marked you. He marked you.
我也要 拜托 - OK
Me, too. Please. -Okay.
谢谢 - 住手
Thank you. -Stop!
住手 别碰他
Stop! Stop touching him!
他们毁了一切
They're ruining everything.
那只些物件
Those are just things.
可以被替换 不用担心
They can be replaced. Don't worry.
原谅我 几张照片而已 - 当然
Forgive me. Just a few shots. -Of course.
来了 - 不
Here we go. -No!
看镜头 把他拍进去
Look right in the lens, make sure you're getting him.
不 别走
No, no, no, no, don't go!
拜托 再来一张
Please, just one more!
请把谢意钉在门上
You're welcome to pin your thanks on the door.
他的语句是描写你的
His words are yours.
请注意脚下
Watch your step going down.
下一个 请 往前走
Next, please. Step forward.
他的语句是描写你的
His words are yours.
如果你愿意 把你的想法钉在墙上
If you please, pin your thoughts on the wall.
往前走
Step forward.
他的语句是描写你的
His words are yours.
下一个
Next.
你在这儿
There you are!
你躲到哪里去了?
Where have you been hiding?
你为什么要这么做?
Why are you doing this?
证明我们在这里
Proof we were here.
放开我 - 见鬼
Get off of me! -What the hell!
我要杀了你
I'll kill you!
小心你的后背 - 抬头 借过
Watch your back. -Heads up. Coming through.
不 不要
No! Don't.
不 放手
No! Let go!
不 你不能走 他爱你
No, you can't leave! He loves you!
我来 你要去哪里?不要 别走
I got it. Where are you going? Don't. Don't go.
你不希望我在这里
You don't want me here.
过来 看这里
Come here. Look here.
我在这里 - 我不能
I'm here. -I can't.
我有事要告诉你
Listen, I have to tell you something.
怎么了?
What?
孩子?
The baby? The baby?
过来 - 锁上后门
Come here. Come, come. -Lock the back door!
我们需要空间
We need space! We need space!
等一下 我马上回来
Hold on here. I'll be right back.
后退 给我们点空间
Back! Back! Give us some room!
警察 趴到地上
Police! Get on the ground!
帮帮我 帮帮我 不
Help me. Help me. No!
靠墙
Against the wall!
请不要 我的孩子 请不要
Please don't! My baby! Please don't!
放开她 放开
Get off her! Get off!
退后
Back off!
我有权利
I call dibs!
你要去哪里?进去
Where are you going? Get inside!
来人救命
Somebody help us, please!
闭嘴
Shut up!
天使怎么样? - 污染
How's Angel? -Tainted.
检查异教徒
Check the goyim.
让开
Move!
我什么都没做 - 进去
I didn't do anything! -Get in there!
安静 - 闭嘴
Quiet! -Keep your mouths shut.
灵感
The inspiration!
你躲到哪里去了?
Where have you been hiding?
干掉她
Finish her.
跪下
On your knees!
好吧 再六个
All right, six more.
分散
Disperse!
不许动
Freeze!
不 快来
No. Come on.
你受伤了吗
Are you hurt?
婴儿
The baby...
医生
Medic!
这边
This way.
快点走
Go, hurry. Just go!
亲爱的 是我
My darling! It's me! It's me.
怎么了?
What's happening?
不知道 我得带你去个安全的地方
I don't know. I have to take you somewhere safe.
那里 - 不
There. -No, no, no.
出去 - 太危险了
Out! -It's too dangerous.
跟我来 别出声
Come with me. Quietly.
这边
This way.
门 - 不 是这边
The door! -No, no, it's this way.
是他 是诗人
It's him! It's the poet!
他还没有抛弃我们
He hasn't forsaken us after all!
我们得快点 别靠近
We need to hurry. Stay close.
我们需要钱 我们要吃东西 拜托
We need money! We need to eat! Please!
退回去 我没办法
Get back! Get back! I can't! I can't!
对不起 我不能
I'm sorry. I'm sorry. I can't!
我不会忘记你
I will not forget you.
诗人 看这里 快
Poet, over here! Come on!
在上面
Up here! Up here!
Up there! Up there.
他们会保护我们的
They will protect us.
我抓到你了
Come. I've got you.
抓住那只手
Grab the hand.
退后 我会回来的
Get back! Get back! I will return!
把他们推回去
Hold them back!
坐这儿 休息
Sit here. Rest.
我是医生 - 医生?请帮助她
I'm a doctor! -A doctor? Please help her.
请帮助她 这里 我马上回来
Help her, please. Here. I'll be right back.
很好
That's good.
别离开我们
Don't leave us!
放开
Get off!
看着我 听我的声音
Look at me. Listen to my voice.
孩子快出来了
The baby's almost here.
再努力一点 你能做到的
Just a little bit further. You can do this.
用力
Push.
Just push.
不 - 对
No. -Yes, yes!
你得用力
You have to push. Push!
用力 就快成了
Push. You're almost there. Yes!
再来一次
Do it again.
你做得很好
Yes, you're doing very good.
我能感觉到头 - 请让开 我来帮她
I can feel the head. -Please move. I've got her.
等等 我能帮你 - 我要接生我的孩子
Wait! I can help. -I'm delivering my baby!
让我帮忙 - 把门关上
Let me help! -Shut the door!
闭嘴
Shut it!
我们很安全
We're safe.
没关系 我们的孩子来了
It's okay. Our baby's coming.
我们的孩子来了
Our baby's coming. Our baby's coming.
Our baby's coming.
OK
Okay.
就快了
It's almost here.
出来了
It's here. It's coming. It's coming!
是个男孩
It's a boy.
男孩 看
It's a boy, look.
男孩
It's a boy.
盖好他
Cover him.
怎么了?
What's happening?
他们为什么这么安静? - 我不知道
Why are they so quiet? -I don't know.
不要
Don't!
别这样
Don't do that.
没事的
It's okay.
关上门
Shut the door.
封门
Seal it!
他们给我们带来了礼物
They brought us gifts.
拿着 - 他们在做什么?
Here. -What are they doing?
他们只是在等
They're just waiting.
等什么?
Waiting for what?
我不知道
I don't know.
让他们走
Make them go.
拜托
Please.
请让他们走
Please make them.
拜托 - OK
Please. -Okay, okay.
更多的礼物 看啊
More gifts. Look. Look.
给你的 干净衣服
For you. Clean clothes.
他们要走了吗
Are they leaving?
什么?
What?
不 他们  他们只是想见见他
No, they... They just want to see him.
不
No.
让他们走
Make them go.
我不能
I can't. I can't.
你可以 他们崇拜你 他们会听你的
Yes, you can! They adore you. They would listen to you.
为什么不 - 我不想让他们走
Why won't you? -I don't want them to go!
他很漂亮
He's beautiful.
让我抱抱 - 不行
Let me hold him. -No.
让我抱抱他
Okay, let me hold him.
让我抱着孩子 - 不
Let me hold my baby. -No.
让我抱抱 - 不行
Let me hold him. -No.
我是他父亲 - 我是他母亲
I'm his father! -I'm his mother!
让我... - 不
Here, let me... -No!
求你
Please?
请让他们走
Please make them go.
不
No. No. No.
No!
把我的孩子还给我
Give me back my baby!
他在哪?
Where is he?
等等 住手
Wait! Stop!
不 那是我的宝贝
No! That's my baby!
不 还给我
No! No! Give me back...
哈利路亚 - 赞美
Hallelujah! -Praise be!
哈利路亚
Hallelujah!
你会伤害他的
You're gonna hurt him!
求你
Please! Please! Please!
你会伤害他的
You're gonna hurt him!
你在伤害他
You're hurting him! You're hurting him!
他在哪?
Where is he?
我的孩子呢 - 他没死
Where's my baby? -He's not dead.
什么?他在哪? - 声音
What? Where is he? -A voice
仍然呼喊着要被听到 响亮强烈
still cries out to be heard, loud and strong.
听 - 什么?
Listen. -What?
你听到了吗
Do you hear that?
不
No! No!
你听到了吗
Do you hear that?
生命的声音
That's the sound of life.
人类的声音
The sound of humanity!
他爱的呐喊
His cry of love!
他对你的爱
His love for you!
扔掉
Get off! Get off!
你们杀了他
You killed him!
去死 婊子 - 肮脏的婊子
Die, cunt! -Dirty whore!
婊子
Slut! Bitch!
肥猪
Fat pig!
你这个
You bitch!
吃一拳 流浪汉
Take that, tramp!
婊子 - 杀了那头猪
Cunt! -Kill the pig!
拜托
Please!
请停下
Please stop! Stop, please!
走开 放开她 你们做什么?
Go away. Leave her alone. What are you doing?
看看他们对你做了什么
Look what they've done to you.
你们干了什么?
What are you doing? What are you doing?
他们杀了我的孩子
They killed my baby!
你杀了他
You killed him.
我很抱歉
I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry.
他们只想见见他 他们只想抚摸他
They just want to see him. They just want to touch him,
然后他们
and then they...
这是
It was...
太可怕了 对不起 我很抱歉
It's horrible. I'm sorry. I'm so sorry.
但我们不能
But we can't...
我们不能让他死得一无所值
We can't let him die for nothing. We can't.
也许发生的一切都能改变一切
Maybe what happened could change everything.
改变所有人
Everyone.
你在说什么? - 我们...
What are you talking about? -We...
你和我 我们必须想办法原谅他们
You and I, we have to find a way to forgive them.
他们屠杀了我们的儿子
They butchered our son!
我知道
I know. I know.
你疯了
You're insane.
听我说 - 你疯了
Listen to me. -You're insane.
听听他们 他们很抱歉
Well, listen to them. They are so sorry.
他们真的很抱歉
They are truly sorry.
对我有信心 务必
Listen. Have faith in me. Please. Please.
我们得原谅他们
We need to forgive them. We need to forgive them!
拜托 我们必须这么做
Please. Please! We have to!
不
No!
杀人犯
Murderers!
凶手
Murderer!
是时候滚出我的房子了
It's time to get the fuck out of my house!
不
No, no. No, no, no!
不 请别走
No! Please! Don't leave!
求你 我求你了
Please! I beg you!
别跑 我们会重建的
Don't run off! We will rebuild!
不要 别丢下我一个人
Don't! Don't leave me alone!
这边 她去了这里
This way! She went down here!
停下 等等
Stop! Stop! Wait. Wait.
不要
Don't! Don't! Don't!
请不要
Please don't.
我爱你
I love you.
你从没爱过我
You never loved me.
你只是爱我爱你
You just loved how much I loved you.
我给了你一切
I gave you everything!
你放弃了一切
You gave it all away.
不
No. No. No.
不要
No, no, no, no!
你是什么?
What are you?
我?
Me?
我是我
I am I.
你?
You?
你回家了
You were home.
你要带我去哪?
Where are you taking me?
源头
The beginning.
是这样吗
Is that it?
不会疼很久的
It won't hurt much longer.
最让我伤心的是 有我还不够
What hurts me the most is that I wasn't enough.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
没有什么是永远不够的
Nothing is ever enough.
我不能创造它 如果它已存在
I couldn't create if it was.
我必须这么做 这就是我
And I have to. That's what I do.
这就是我
That's what I am.
现在我必须再试一次
Now I must try it all again.
不
No.
让我走吧
Just let me go.
我需要最后一样东西
I need one last thing.
我没有什么可给的了
I have nothing left to give.
你的爱
Your love.
它还在那里 不是吗
It's still there, isn't it?
继续
Go ahead.
拿去吧
Take it.
宝贝?
Baby?